Kirill Tamogashev

■ tamogachev@icloud.com | inkedin.com/in/kirill-tamogashev

Personal Profile ___

Driven and accomplished Math of Machine Learning Master's student at Skoltech and Higher School of Economics, consistently delivering strong academic performance. I possess a deep passion for the field and actively seek opportunities to contribute my skills and knowledge to the research and development of Artificial Intelligence and Deep Learning algorithms.

Skills and Knowledge

Deep Learning Neural Signal Processing, NLP, Transformers, Bayesian Methods, VAE, Diffusion models

Programming Python (strong knowledge of PyTorch), NumPy, Scikit-learn, C++

Miscellaneous Linux, Shell (Bash/Zsh), Docker, CI/CD, Git.

Languages Russian (Native), English, German

Education_

Yandex School of Data Analysis

Moscow, Russia

Supplementary Education

September 2023 - Current

• Courses: Advanced Algorithms and Data Structures, C++, Tensor Decompositions

Skolkovo Institute of Science and Technology & National Research University Higher School of Economics

Moscow, Russia

Joint MSc degree in Math of Machine Learning

September 2022 - Current

• GPA - 9.19

· Courses: Measure Theory, Markov Chains, High-Dimensional Probability and Statistics, Neurobayesian Methods

National Research University Higher School of Economics

Moscow, Russia

BSc in Economics

September 2018 - August 2022

• GPA - 8.16

• Courses: Probability Theory, Stochastic Processes, Machine Learning, Reinforcement Learning

Work Experience ____

Samsung Al Center Moscow, Russia

Al Researcher

- Key responsibility: developing the algorithm for acoustic domain transfer.
- · Contributed to the design of augmentations used for training speech enhancement for portable devices.

· Conducted research on the effects of various audio degradations on the quality of a trained speech enhancement model.

• During my work I gained a strong understanding of techniques employed in neural signal processing.

Samsung Al Center Moscow, Russia

Intern Al Researcher

June 2023 - July 2023

August 2023 - Current

- Researched techniques for faster diffusion distillation.
- Implemented novel diffusion distillation technique from scratch.

TinkoffMoscow, Russia

ML Engineer

November 2021 - June 2023

Played a key role in developing, maintaining, and deploying efficient text-to-speech models, with a focus on enhancing speaker quality and

prosodic diversity of production models.

• Successfully improved speaker quality and prosodic diversity by 5-10%, resulting in a more natural and engaging audio experience.

National Research University Higher School of Economics

Moscow, Russia

October 2019 - May 2022

Teaching Assistant

• Courses: Probability Theory and Statistics, Calculus, Linear Algebra, Deep Learning, Machine Learning

Recognized as one of the brightest students with excellent grades for the corresponding subjects.